# **EMILIE D'OLNE**

Room 809, Electrical and Electronic Engineering, Imperial College London, SW7 2AZ +44 7756 721158 <a href="mailto:emilie.dolne16@imperial.ac.uk">emilie.dolne16@imperial.ac.uk</a> <a href="www.linkedin.com/in/emiliedolne">www.linkedin.com/in/emiliedolne</a>

# Research interests

My current research focuses on the development of speech enhancement algorithms for hearing aids, with a specific focus on people suffering from dementia-induced hearing impairments. I am part of a clinician project in collaboration with University College London looking at hearing in dementia. My role includes the development of listening tests and assistive technologies for patients affected by dementia syndromes. I am interested in exploiting distributed microphone networks and wearable microphones for enhancement and denoising and am working with techniques such as binaural beamforming and polynomial eigenvalue decomposition (PEVD).

# Education

### PhD - Speech and Audio Processing

2020-PRESENT

Imperial College London, Communications and Signal Processing Research Group Interests in binaural beamforming, dereverberation, speech enhancement, wearable microphone arrays, distributed microphone networks, machine learning, deep learning.

MEng – Electrical and Electronics Engineering (First Class Honours) 2016-2020

Imperial College London, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department

Final year project: "Automatic detection of Alzheimer's Disease using speech"

Certificat d'Enseignement Secondaire Supérieur (A-levels equiv.) 2010-2016

Athénée Royal Charles Rogier Liège 1, Liège, Belgium

# **Projects**

Synergising Markers, Tests and Technologies to Enable Real-world Hearing in Alzheimer's and Related dementias (SMarTTER HeAR) 2022-PRESENT

Discovery Research Grant (RNID and Alzheimer's research UK), University College London

Responsible for the "technology" side and participating in the design of listening tests.

# Experience

#### Vice-Chair, Treasurer

2021-PRESENT

Imperial College IEEE Student branch

Organisation of technical seminars and workshops, monitoring of the branch's finances.

# Postgraduate Student Representative

2021-PRESENT

Imperial College London, Communications and Signal Processing Research Group

Representing students' interests within the department and at the university.

### **Teaching Assistant**

2019-PRESENT

Imperial College London, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department

Teaching, development of materials, assessment, and support.

Research Intern SUMMER 2019

Imperial College London, Speech and Audio Processing Laboratory

Gaze-directed beamforming for hearing aids in collaboration with Cardiff University.

### **Publications**

- [1] **E. d'Olne**, V. W. Neo, and P. A. Naylor, "Speech Enhancement in Distributed Microphone Arrays Using Polynomial Eigenvalue Decomposition", 2022 [Submitted to *Proc. Eur. Signal Process. Conf. (EUSIPCO)*]
- [2] **E. d'Olne**, A. H. Moore, and P. A. Naylor, "Model-based beamforming for wearable microphone arrays", in *Proc. Eur. Signal Process. Conf. (EUSIPCO)*, Dublin, Ireland, 2021.

### **Awards**

### Institute of Engineering and Technology (IET) Prize

2020

Imperial College London, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department

### Dean's List for Academic Excellence

2018,2019,2020

Imperial College London, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department

# Skills and Languages

**Technical skills** MATLAB, Python, TensorFlow, C++, GitHub, Linux, HTML/CSS **Languages** French (bilingual), Spanish (intermediate), German (intermediate)